Hello, I am Dr. Afif. In this video,
I welcome you all. In today’s video,
I will talk about an important topic,
and that is sexual health.
There are some common misconceptions in our society.
Many people feel scared or ashamed about this topic.
Some even fall victim to wrong treatments. So today,
we will dispel these misconceptions in the light of science.
Watch the video till the end and share it with your friends
because this information is necessary for everyone to know.
Talking about sexuality in our society is still
considered a taboo, which has led to many misconceptions spreading.
Many people come to me saying
they masturbate and fear that it will weaken their body.
Some try to test their sexual ability before marriage
and end up facing problems, thinking they have a permanent issue.
Others get alarmed after seeing misleading posters or advertisements
claiming "100% guaranteed treatment," but these
are often unscientific and harmful. Today, we will
clear these misconceptions and provide accurate information.
The first misconception is that masturbation weakens the body.
Many believe
that masturbation causes the body to weaken, reduces sexual strength,
or harms health. This is a misconception.
It doesn’t cause any loss of nutrients like vitamins or
minerals, so there’s no need to fear this.
Now, let’s move to the second misconception:
Semen is made from blood, and its release weakens the body.
There’s a common belief in our society that semen is made from blood,
so when it’s released, the body becomes weak.
But this is a misconception. Semen is produced in the reproductive system,
and its release has no connection to the body’s strength or health.
It’s a natural process. The next misconception is that
if a sticky substance comes out with urine, it’s harmful.
Many people get scared when they see a slippery or sticky substance
during urination or sexual arousal, thinking it’s semen or harmful.
In reality, this is a natural bodily process called pre-ejaculate.
It helps with lubrication and doesn’t harm the body.
The next misconception is that sexual ability depends on penis size.
Many believe
that sexual ability depends on the size or shape of the penis.
This is a misconception. Sexual satisfaction
actually depends on emotional connection, communication,
and mutual understanding with your partner.
Also, masturbation doesn’t make the penis smaller or thinner—
this is another baseless fear.
The next misconception is that wet dreams are a sign of illness.
Many feel ashamed or scared about wet dreams,
but it’s a natural occurrence, especially during puberty
and adulthood. It’s not a sign of disease or sexual weakness.
There’s no need to worry about it. Some men think
that if sexual intercourse lasts only a few minutes, they have a problem.
But an average duration of 3 to 5 minutes is normal for about 90% of people.
Sexual satisfaction doesn’t depend on time
but on mutual enjoyment and connection. Plus,
there are techniques to increase duration if needed.
Some men, before marriage, test their sexual ability with girlfriends
or sex workers and face problems, thinking it’s permanent.
But these issues are often due to mental stress or lack of experience.
With time and a calm mind, it improves.
There’s no need to test this before marriage.
Problems during the first sexual experience are common.
Now, let’s talk about misleading advertisements.
You might have seen posters claiming "100% guaranteed treatment."
These ads often scare people into trying unscientific treatments,
which can be extremely harmful to your health.
If you have any sexual health issues, always consult
a qualified, registered doctor. So, how can we lead a healthy sexual life?
First, stay stress-free. Mental stress or fear
can greatly affect your sexual health.
Second, talk openly with your partner—communication is very important.
Third, if there’s a problem, avoid unscientific treatments
and consult a registered doctor. Lastly,
learn about your body and overcome misconceptions to build confidence.
I hope today’s video will be helpful to you.
Like this video, share it,
and subscribe to our channel and page
so you can get more educational videos like this.
If you have any questions, let me know in the comments—
I’ll try to answer them. Stay healthy, stay confident.
Thank you, and see you again!